fakespot.com 2019-12-24

# Fakespot

## **Fakespot Privacy Policy – Effective November 13, 2019**

###  Introduction

Thank you for using Fakespot. Our mission is to bring transparency and trust back to the Internet. As part of that mission, we believe it is important to be open and clear with our users on what personal information we collect and how we use it. To be clear, we do not sell or transfer any user’s personal information. We may share your personal information only to maintain and improve the Service for you. This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you use our website ([www.fakespot.com](http://www.fakespot.com/)) and our software applications (browser extensions and mobile apps) (collectively the “Service” or “Services”).

### Personal Information We Collect

When you use our Services, we automatically collect the following information about you (collectively referred to as “Personal Information”):

  * Your device information which includes, but is not limited to, information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device
  * Individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Service, and information about how you interact with the Service
  * Your first and last name
  * Your email address
  * Your username associated with your Apple ID or Google Account

### We collect Personal Information using the following technologies:

   \- “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

   \- “Log files” track actions occurring on the Service, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.

   \- “Web beacons,” “tags,” and “pixels” are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Service.

### How do we use your Personal Information?

We may use your personal information in several ways:

  * Serve you advertising from our advertising partners;
  * Provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services;
  * Store your product analysis and search history on the Service;
  * Screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address); and
  * To improve and optimize our Service (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Service, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns).

### Sharing your Personal Information

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use your Personal Information, as described above. We use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Service. You can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: [https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/). You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

As described above, we may use your Personal Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) educational page at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work](http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work).

You can opt out of targeted advertising here: 

Google - [https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous)

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out portal at: [http://optout.aboutads.info/](http://optout.aboutads.info/).

### Do not track

Please note that we do not alter our Service’s data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

### Your Rights

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please email us at [contact@fakespot.com ](mailto:contact@fakespot.com)with the subject “GDPR Request” and please provide your specific request within the body of the email so we can efficiently accommodate your request.

Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you, or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Additionally, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including to the United States.

### Data Retention

When you use the Service, we will retain your Personal Information and use it as described above unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

### Minors

You must be at least 13 years old to use the Service. The Service complies with the rules of the Children’s Online Privacy Protect Act (“COPPA”). Accordingly, the Service does not permit anyone under the age of 13 to use the Service. In addition, the Service does not knowingly collect or solicit any information from anyone under the age of 13. If the Service unknowingly collects personal information from a child under the age of 13 without parental consent, we will delete that information as soon as possible. Please contact us at [contact@fakespot.com ](mailto:contact@fakespot.com)with the subject “COPPA” if you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13.

### Links to Other Websites

As part of the Service, we may provide links to or compatibility with other websites or applications. However, we are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by those websites or the information or content they contain. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by us through the Service. Therefore, this Privacy Policy does not apply to your use of a third-party website or application accessed by selecting a link provided on the Service. To the extent that you access or use the Service through or on another website or application, then the privacy policy of that other website or application will apply to your access or use of that site or application. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of other websites or applications before proceeding to use them.

### Changes

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

### Contact Us

For more information about our privacy policy or if you have any questions please contact us by e-mail at [contact@fakespot.com](mailto:contact@fakespot.com?subject=Privacy%2520Policy%2520Question) with the subject “Privacy Policy Question”.
